Guide to the Edna Clare Bryner Papers, 1919-1955
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Edna Clare Bryner Papers
1919-1955
Bryner, Edna, 1886-1967
5 cubic feet (27 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence, primarily letters received, 1919-1955, concerning a European trip, publishing, translations of her work, comment on her writing, contracts, and personal affairs; manuscripts and typescripts of her novels and short stories primarily from the 1920s and 1930s; her notes concerning Tibetan Buddhist literature; and photographs and other miscellaneous items.
Biographical Note
Edna Bryner was born in Tylersburg, Pennsylvania, in 1866 and graduated from Vassar in 1907. After college she worked at a number of jobs, including serving on the staff of the Russell Sage Foundation for five years. During that period she conducted a study of the garment trades in Cleveland and directed a housing survey of New York City. After 1918 she devoted herself to writing short stories and novels. A critic wrote of her first novel Andy Brandt's Ark that "from it one learns a great deal about how a fairly typical young woman of the newest vintage thinks and feels." Bryner married Arthur Schwab in 1916 but continued to use her maiden name.
In 1939 her interest in Asian religions led her to seek instruction from professor Bernhard Geiger, a philologist at Columbia. She became an expert on Tibetan Buddhist literature and was asked by the City Art Museum of St. Louis to make a study of a series of Tibetan temple paintings it had purchased. Her Thirteen Tibetan Tankas is an important contribution to the study of the rebirth doctrine in Buddhism.
Bryner died in 1967.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, primarily letters received, 1919-1955, concerning a European trip, publishing, translations of her work, comment on her writing, contracts, and personal affairs; manuscripts and typescripts of her novels and short stories primarily from the 1920s and 1930s; her notes concerning Tibetan Buddhist literature; and photographs and other miscellaneous items.
Note: The drafts of Bryner's manuscripts were ordered and numbered by the archivist and do not necessarily reflect Bryner's order of progress.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Subjects:
Buddhist literature, Tibetan
Places:
Europe--Description and travel
Document Types:
Photographs
VCL Categories
Literature and Writing; Travel
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, November 2006.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Estate of Edna Bryner (Mrs. Arthur Schwab).
Container List
- Items about Edna Bryner's publications, copies of stories from periodicals, short manuscripts, notes, and miscellaneous items (Folders 1.1 – 1.2)
- Correspondence — Business related, 1919-1926 (Folder 1.3)
- Correspondence — Business related, 1927-1948, n.d. (Folder 1.4)
- Correspondence — Personal, 1924-1948 (Folder 1.5)
- The Close-Up, (2 copies) (Folder 1.6)
- Between Generations (Folder 1.7)
- Black Heart, Come White (Folder 1.8)
- The Ballad of Hannah Silvis (Folder 1.9)
- An American Experience (Folder 1.10)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 1 – 40, (TS) (Folder 2.11)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 41 – 80, (TS) (Folder 2.12)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 81 – 120, (TS) (Folder 2.13)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 121 – 160, (TS) (Folder 2.14)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 161 – 200, (TS) (Folder 2.15)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 201 – 240, (TS) (Folder 2.16)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 241 – 280, (TS) (Folder 2.17)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 281 – 320, (TS) (Folder 2.18)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 321 – 360, (TS) (Folder 2.19)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 261 – 400, (TS) (Folder 2.20)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 401 – 440, (TS) (Folder 2.21)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 441 – 480, (TS) (Folder 2.22)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 481 – 520, (TS) (Folder 2.23)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 521 – 560, (TS) (Folder 2.24)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 561 – 600, (TS) (Folder 2.25)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 601 – 640, (TS) (Folder 3.26)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 641 – 680, (TS) (Folder 3.27)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 681 – 720, (TS) (Folder 3.28)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 721 – 760, (TS) (Folder 3.29)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 761 – 800, (TS) (Folder 3.30)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 801 – 850, (TS) (Folder 3.31)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 851 – 900, (TS) (Folder 3.32)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 901 – 950, (TS) (Folder 3.33)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 951 – 1000, (TS) (Folder 3.34)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 1001 – 1050, (TS) (Folder 3.35)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 1051 – 1100, (TS) (Folder 4.36)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 1101 – 1150, (TS) (Folder 4.37)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 1151 – 1200, (TS) (Folder 4.38)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 1201 – 1250, (TS) (Folder 4.39)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 1251 – 1300, (TS) (Folder 4.40)
- Crossways, draft 1, pp. 1301 – 1348, (TS) (Folder 4.41)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 1 – 40, (TS) (Folder 4.42)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 41 – 80, (TS) (Folder 4.43)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 81 – 120, (TS) (Folder 4.44)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 121 – 160, (TS) (Folder 5.45)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 161 – 200, (TS) (Folder 5.46)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 201 – 240, (TS) (Folder 5.47)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 241 – 280, (TS) (Folder 5.48)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 281 – 320, (TS) (Folder 5.49)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 321 – 360, (TS) (Folder 5.50)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 361 – 400, (TS) (Folder 5.51)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 401 – 450, (TS) (Folder 5.52)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 451 – 500, (TS) (Folder 5.53)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 501 – 550, (TS) (Folder 5.54)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 551 – 600, (TS) (Folder 6.55)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 601 – 650, (TS) (Folder 6.56)
- Crossways, draft 2,, pp. 651 – 700, (TS) (Folder 6.57)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 701 – 750, (TS) (Folder 6.58)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 751 – 800, (TS) (Folder 6.59)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 801 – 850, (TS) (Folder 6.60)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 851 – 900, (TS) (Folder 6.61)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 901 – 950, (TS) (Folder 6.62)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 951 – 1000, (TS) (Folder 6.63)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 1001 – 1050, (TS) (Folder 7.64)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 1051 – 1100, (TS) (Folder 7.65)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 1101 – 1150, (TS) (Folder 7.66)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 1151 – 1200, (TS) (Folder 7.67)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 1201 – 1250, (TS) (Folder 7.68)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 1251 – 1300, (TS) (Folder 7.69)
- Crossways, draft 2, pp. 1301 – 1348, (TS) (Folder 7.70)
- Earth Saga, (TS) (Folder 7.71)
- Fixed, (TS) (Folder 7.72)
- Forest Dweller, (TS) (Folder 7.73)
- As a Lute that Liest Still, pp. 1 – 50, (TS) (Folder 8.74)
- As a Lute that Liest Still, pp. 51 – 100, (TS) (Folder 8.75)
- As a Lute that Liest Still, pp. 101 – 150, (TS) (Folder 8.76)
- As a Lute that Liest Still, pp. 151 – 200, (TS) (Folder 8.77)
- As a Lute that Liest Still, pp. 201 – 250, (TS) (Folder 8.78)
- As a Lute that Liest Still, pp. 251 – 300, (TS) (Folder 8.79)
- As a Lute that Liest Still, pp. 301 – 350, (TS) (Folder 8.80)
- As a Lute that Liest Still, pp. 351 – 400, (TS) (Folder 8.81)
- As a Lute that Liest Still, pp. 401 – 450, (TS) (Folder 8.82)
- As a Lute that Liest Still, pp. 451 – 491, (TS) (Folder 8.83)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 1, pp. 1 – 50, (TS) (Folder 9.84)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 1, pp. 51 – 100, (TS) (Folder 9.85)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 1, pp. 101 – 150, (TS) (Folder 9.86)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 1, pp. 151 – 200, (TS) (Folder 9.87)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 1, pp. 201 – 250, (TS) (Folder 9.88)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 1, pp. 251 – 300, (TS) (Folder 9.89)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 1, pp. 301 – 350, (TS) (Folder 9.90)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 1, pp. 351 – 374, (TS) (Folder 9.91)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 2, pp. 1 – 50, (TS) (Folder 10.92)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 2, pp. 51 – 100, (TS) (Folder 10.93)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 2, pp. 101 – 150, (TS) (Folder 10.94)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 2, pp. 151 – 200, (TS) (Folder 10.95)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 2, pp. 201 – 250, (TS) (Folder 10.96)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 2, pp. 251 – 300, (TS) (Folder 10.97)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 2, pp. 301 – 350, (TS) (Folder 10.98)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 2, pp. 351 – 274, (TS) (Folder 10.99)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 3, pp. 1 – 50, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 11.100)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 3, pp. 51 – 100, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 11.101)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 3, pp. 101 – 150, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 11.102)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 3, pp. 151 – 200, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 11.103)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 3, pp. 201 – 250, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 11.104)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 3, pp. 251 – 300, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 11.105)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 3, pp. 301 – 350, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 11.106)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 3, pp. 351 – 400, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 11.107)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 3, pp. 401 – 450, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 11.108)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 3, pp. 451 – 491, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 11.109)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 4, pp. 1 – 50, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 12.110)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 4, pp. 51 – 100, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 12.111)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 4, pp. 101 – 150, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 12.112)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 4, pp. 151 – 200, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 12.113)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 4, pp. 201 – 250, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 12.114)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 4, pp. 251 – 300, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 12.115)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 4, pp. 301 – 350, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 12.116)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 4, pp. 351 – 400, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 12.117)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 4, pp. 401 – 450, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 12.118)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 4, pp. 451 – 500, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 12.119)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 4, pp. 501 – 550, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 12.120)
- How Shall a Lute Be Made to Sing, draft 4, pp. 551 – 580, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 12.121)
- Earth Saga John Butterfield's Memory, draft 1 (Folder 13.122)
- John Butterfield's Memory, draft 2 (Folder 13.123)
- The Little Fly, draft 1 (Folder 13.124)
- The Little Fly, draft 2 (Folder 13.125)
- The Market, draft 1, (TS, carbon with handwritten notes) (Folder 13.126)
- The Market, draft 2, pp. 4 - 17 missing, (TS, carbon with handwritten notes) (Folder 13.127)
- Number Fantasy, draft 2, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 13.128)
- Number Fantasy, draft 2, (Corrected TS) (Folder 13.129)
- Peter the Great from Holland's Magazine, April 1923 (Folder 13.130)
- Peter the Great, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 13.131)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 1, pp. 1 – 50, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 14.132)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 1, pp. 51 – 100, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 14.133)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 1, pp. 101 – 150, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 14.134)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 1, pp. 151 – 200, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 14.135)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 1, pp. 201 – 250, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 14.136)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 1, pp. 251 – 300, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 14.137)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 1, pp. 301 – 350, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 14.138)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 1, pp. 351 – 401, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 14.139)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 2, pp. 1 – 50, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 15.140)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 2, pp. 51 – 100, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 15.141)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 2, pp. 101 – 150, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 15.142)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 2, pp. 151 – 200, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 15.143)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 2, pp. 201 – 250, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 15.144)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 2, pp. 251 – 300, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 15.145)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 2, pp. 301 – 350, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 15.146)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 2, pp. 351 – 400, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 15.147)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 2, pp. 401 – 450, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 15.148)
- Margot Amering or a Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 2, pp. 451 – 473, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 15.149)
- [Margot Amering or] A Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 3, pp. 1 – 48, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 16.150)
- [Margot Amering or] A Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 3, pp. 51 – 100, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 16.151)
- [Margot Amering or] A Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 3, pp. 101 – 150, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 16.152)
- [Margot Amering or] A Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 3, pp. 151 – 200, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 16.153)
- [Margot Amering or] A Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 3, pp. 201 – 250, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 16.154)
- [Margot Amering or] A Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 3, pp. 251 – 300, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 16.155)
- [Margot Amering or] A Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 3, pp. 301 – 350, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 16.156)
- [Margot Amering or] A Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 3, pp. 351 – 400, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 16.157)
- [Margot Amering or] A Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 3, pp. 401 – 450, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 16.158)
- [Margot Amering or] A Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 3, pp. 451 – 470, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 16.159)
- [Margot Amering or] A Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 4, pp. 1 – 50, (TS with handwritten and typed corrections) (Folder 17.160)
- [Margot Amering or] A Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 4, pp. 51 - 100, (TS with handwritten and typed corrections) (Folder 17.161)
- [Margot Amering or] A Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 4, pp. 101 – 150, (TS with handwritten and typed corrections) (Folder 17.162)
- [Margot Amering or] A Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 4, pp. 151 – 200, (TS with handwritten and typed corrections) (Folder 17.163)
- [Margot Amering or] A Modern Maiden's Calendar, draft 4, pp. 201 - 225, (TS with handwritten and typed corrections) (Folder 17.164)
- A Martin Water Color Adventure, 2 drafts (Folder 17.165)
- Mountain Mind, draft 1, pp. 1 – 25, (unmarked TS) (Folder 17.166)
- Mountain Mind, draft 2, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 17.167)
- Mountain Mind, draft 3, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 17.168)
- Mountain Mind, draft 4, (TS with typed corrections) (Folder 17.169)
- A Pilgrim Picture-Book, draft 1, pp. 1 – 50, (TS with handwritten and typed corrections) (Folder 18.170)
- A Pilgrim Picture-Book, draft 1, pp. 51 – 100, (TS with handwritten and typed corrections) (Folder 18.171)
- A Pilgrim Picture-Book, draft 1, pp. 101 – 150, (TS with handwritten and typed corrections) (Folder 18.172)
- A Pilgrim Picture-Book, draft 1, pp. 151 – 200, (TS with handwritten and typed corrections) (Folder 18.173)
- A Pilgrim Picture-Book, draft 1, pp. 201 – 250, (TS with handwritten and typed corrections) (Folder 18.174)
- A Pilgrim Picture-Book, draft 1, pp. 251 – 300, (TS with handwritten and typed corrections) (Folder 18.175)
- A Pilgrim Picture-Book, draft 1, pp. 251 – 300, (TS with handwritten and typed corrections) (Folder 18.176)
- A Pilgrim Picture-Book, draft 2, pp. 1 – 50, (TS with typed corrections and handwritten notes) (Folder 19.177)
- A Pilgrim Picture-Book, draft 2, pp. 51 – 100, (TS with typed corrections and handwritten notes) (Folder 19.178)
- A Pilgrim Picture-Book, draft 2, pp. 101 – 150, (TS with typed corrections and handwritten notes) (Folder 19.179)
- A Pilgrim Picture-Book, draft 2, pp. 151 – 200, (TS with typed corrections and handwritten notes) (Folder 19.180)
- A Pilgrim Picture-Book, draft 2, pp. 201 – 250, (TS with typed corrections and handwritten notes) (Folder 19.181)
- A Pilgrim Picture-Book, draft 2, pp. 251 – 300, (TS with typed corrections and handwritten notes) (Folder 19.182)
- A Pilgrim Picture-Book, draft 2, pp. 301 – 350, (TS with typed corrections and handwritten notes) (Folder 19.183)
- Prelude and Fugue, pp. 1 – 30, (TS) (Folder 20.184)
- Prelude and Fugue, pp. 31 – 56, (TS) (Folder 20.185)
- A Romantic Prelude, (TS) (Folder 20.186)
- Spanish Delight, draft 1, pp. 1 – 50, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 20.187)
- Spanish Delight, draft 1, pp. 51 – 100, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 20.188)
- Spanish Delight, draft 1, pp. 101 – 150, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 20.189)
- Spanish Delight, draft 1, pp. 151 – 200, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 20.190)
- Spanish Delight, draft 1, pp. 201 – 259, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 20.191)
- Spanish Delight, draft 2 - Counsel, pp. 1 – 40, (TS) (Folder 21.192)
- Spanish Delight, draft 2 - Counsel, pp. 41 – 86, (TS) (Folder 21.193)
- Spanish Delight, draft 2 - Throne and Angels, pp. 1 – 24, (TS) (Folder 21.194)
- Spanish Delight, draft 2 - The Baroque of Mithra, pp. 1 – 26, (TS) (Folder 21.195)
- Spanish Delight, draft 2 - Where Angels Do Not Fear to Tread, pp. 1 – 26, (TS) (Folder 21.196)
- Spanish Delight, draft 2 - Beating of Wings, pp. 1 – 30, (TS) (Folder 21.197)
- Spanish Delight, draft 2 - Beating of Wings, pp. 31 – 61, (TS) (Folder 21.198)
- Spanish Delight, draft 2 - Beautific Vision, miscellaneous pages and notes, (TS) (Folder 21.199)
- Spanish Delight, draft 2 - Beautific Vision, pp. 1 – 36, (TS) (Folder 21.200)
- Spanish Delight, draft 3, pp. 1 – 50, (TS with typed and handwritten corrections) (Folder 22.201)
- Spanish Delight, draft 3, pp. 51 – 100, (TS with typed and handwritten corrections) (Folder 22.202)
- Spanish Delight, draft 3, pp. 101 – 150, (TS with typed and handwritten corrections) (Folder 22.203)
- Spanish Delight, draft 3, pp. 151 – 200, (TS with typed and handwritten corrections) (Folder 22.204)
- Spanish Delight, draft 3, (TS with typed and handwritten corrections) (Folder 22.205)
- Spanish Delight, draft 4, pp. 1 – 50, (TS with typed and handwritten corrections) (Folder 22.206)
- Spanish Delight, draft 4, pp. 51 – 100, (TS with typed and handwritten corrections) (Folder 22.207)
- Spanish Delight, draft 4, pp. 101 – 150, (TS with typed and handwritten corrections) (Folder 22.208)
- Spanish Delight, draft 4, pp. 151 – 200, (TS with typed and handwritten corrections) (Folder 22.209)
- Spanish Delight, draft 4, pp. 201 – 250, (TS with typed and handwritten corrections) (Folder 23.210)
- Spanish Delight, draft 4, pp. 251 - 257, pp. 250 – 259, (TS with typed and handwritten corrections) (Folder 23.211)
- A Story Ordered, The Century Magazine (Folder 23.212)
- A Story Ordered, draft 1, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 23.213)
- A Story Ordered, draft 2, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 23.214)
- The Strict Account, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 23.215)
- Thirteen Tibetan Tankas, (TS with handwritten corrections, also 5 pages of handwritten notes) (Folder 23.216)
- The Wall of the Sea, draft 1, (TS with handwritten notes) (Folder 23.217)
- The Wall of the Sea, draft 2, (TS with handwritten corrections) (Folder 23.218)
- While the Bridegroom Tarried, pp. 1 – 50, (TS) (Folder 24.219)
- While the Bridegroom Tarried, pp. 51 – 100, (TS) (Folder 24.220)
- While the Bridegroom Tarried, pp. 101 – 150, (TS) (Folder 24.221)
- While the Bridegroom Tarried, pp. 151 – 200, (TS) (Folder 24.222)
- While the Bridegroom Tarried, pp. 201 – 250, (TS) (Folder 24.223)
- While the Bridegroom Tarried, pp. 251 – 300, (TS) (Folder 24.224)
- While the Bridegroom Tarried, pp. 301 – 349, (TS) (Folder 24.225)
- The Year at Boiling Spring, (TS) (Folder 24.226)
- Yes and No in the Provinces, pp. 1 – 50, (TS) (Folder 24.227)
- Yes and No in the Provinces, pp. 51 – 100, (TS) (Folder 24.228)
- A Pali Reader, by Dines Andersen, Ph.D., 1907 (Folder 25.229)
- Pali: Bryner's notes and translations (Folder 25.230)
- Pali: Bryner's notes and translations (Folder 25.231)
- Pali: Bryner's notes and translations (Folder 25.232)
- Pali: Bryner's notes and translations (Folder 25.233)
- Pali: Bryner's notes and translations (Folder 25.234)
- Pali: Bryner's notes and translations (Folder 25.235)
- Pali: Bryner's notes and translations (Folder 25.236)
- Pali: Bryner's notes and translations (Folder 25.237)
- Pali: Bryner's notes and translations (Folder 26.238)
- Pali: Bryner's notes and translations (Folder 26.239)
- Pali: Bryner's notes and translations (Folder 26.240)
- Pali: Bryner's notes and translations (Folder 26.241)
- Pali: Bryner's notes and translations (Folder 26.242)
- Dzanglun: Bryner's notes and translations (Folder 26.243)
- Dzanglun: Bryner's notes and translations (Folder 26.244)
- Photographs: Edna Bryner, Arthur Schwab, Hamersley Manufacturing Company (Folder 27.245)